{
    "id": "e1de0938f142443a9ce8e3da3dae9d33",
    "title": "Identify The Conditional",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6fa1c16be321481092914c8665a6d127",
            "title": "Identify The Conditional",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If you want to learn a musical instrument, you have to practice.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I have enough time tomorrow, I will come and see you.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you answered enough questions, you would pass.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you eat too much, you will get fat.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If she arrived now, we could go to the movies.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If it is fine tomorrow, I will paint the walls.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It would be nice if you cooked dinner today.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will get up earlier if there is a good reason to.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If we had enough money we could buy a car.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I had won the race, I would have made my parents proud.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you had asked me more nicely, I might have bought you a drink.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you heat ice it melts.",
                    "description": "In the zero conditional we use a present tense in both clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}